New York StateWide Senior Action Council; Records apap111
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Subject Files, 1974-1979; 1983-1999; 4; 9.58 cubic ft.
  - Consumer Fraud, 1988-1994; 4.3; 0.25 cubic ft.
    These records document the work of NYSSAC in supporting legislation that would help senior citizens avoid becoming victims of consumer fraud. They include legislative memorandums, manuals, reports and correspondence on topics such as item pricing for electronically scanned items, funeral home legislation, and utility pricing.
    - Student Association of the State University (SASU) response to the Governor's Budget, 1995 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 16)
    - Tax Cut Opposition, 1995 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 17)
    - Testimony Before Subcommittee on Aging, by Bonnie Ray, 1986 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 18)
    - Testimony on Banking Bill by Greg Olsen, Public Hearing, 1994 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 19)
    - TRIAD-Police Relations, Orange County, NY case, 1995-1996 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 20)
    - TRIAD Program, Anti-Crime Bill S-4540-A / A-6706-A, 1993-1995 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 21)
    - University at Buffalo, State University of New York, Research Agreement, 1989 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 22)
    - University at Buffalo, State University of New York, Research Project, 1989 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 23)
    - Violent Crime Initiative, 1995 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 24)
    - Women's Issues, 1993 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Rural Senior Health Organizing Project, 1988-1990; 4.4; 0.15 cubic ft.
    These records contain subject files directly related to the work of the Rural Senior Health Organizing Project (RSHOP), a project involving members from various regional councils of NYSSAC. They include informational material used specifically by RSHOP on topics relating to health care access and health quality issues for seniors living in rural areas of New York State. Included are reports, correspondence and Board meeting packets.
    - Comprehensive Long Term Care Plan for Northeastern New York, 1989 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 37)
    - RSHOP (Rural Senior Health Organizing Project) Board Meeting Packet, 1988 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 38)
    - RSHOP Board Meeting Packet, 1990-1991 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 39)
    - RSHOP Health Care Materials, 1989-1991 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 40)
    - RSHOP Political Action Materials, 1989-1991 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 41)
    - Rural Health Council Report, 1999 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 42)
- Memorabilia, 1985; 2000; 5; 1.06 cubic ft.
  This series contains memorabilia of the New York State Senior Action Council; T-shirts from the NYSSAC Convention of 2000, baseball-style caps, tote bags and assorted pins and buttons. They are decorated with the NYSSAC logo and various slogans in support of the Prescription Drug Bill, to protest Medicare cuts, advocate Senior Power and commemorate 50 years of Social Security. Included is a ceramic coffee mug commemorating NYSSAC's 25th Anniversary.
  Arranged by format
  - NYSSAC Baseball-style Hat (Oversize 1)
  - T-shirt (Oversize 1)
  - Assorted Pins and Buttons (Oversize 1)
  - Ceramic Coffee Mug Commemorating NYSSAC's 25th Anniversary (Box 2 (5-Memorabilia))